You have three layers of resources you have to ask yourself:
how much I have left today? From easy to hard.
The first layer is time. It's easy to think:
I still have three hours until I wrap up the day,
and I have a critical task that I have to finish.
Easy. Just take two hours, so I can finish them.
I don't have enough time for this for today, so I'll push it tomorrow.
The second layer is about thinking.
You have three hours left. It doesn't mean you can think for three hours.
Nobody can think for eight hours a day,
even if you have 8 working hours a day.
Do I have to think this problem, make a decision today,
or is that a tomorrow problem?
The third layer is emotional resource.
It's the hard one. It's hard to gauge. A lot of people don't even realize it.
Because hard conversations, performance management conversations,
escalations, conflicts, urgencies,
they all cost you emotional resources.
So this is the time you ask yourself:
I do have time today. I do have thinking power today.
Do I still have enough emotional resources today?
Maybe some of the things couldn't be done today,
simply because you don't have enough emotional reserve.
So these are the three layers of things you ask yourself,
and you can make better decisions at the right time.